Marion Nestle Papers, 1970-2017 MSS.159
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: What to Eat
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [9 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [10 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [11 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat 1st Pass Pages [12 of 12], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [1 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [2 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [3 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [4 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages (photocopies) [1 of 4], November 16, 2005; December 8, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages (photocopies) [2 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages (photocopies) [3 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages (photocopies) [4 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat First Pass Pages [1 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat First Pass Pages [2 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat First Pass Pages [3 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat First Pass Pages [4 of 4], November 16, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [1 of 4], November 21, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [2 of 4], November 21, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [3 of 4], November 21, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat - 1st Pass Pages [4 of 4], Novemeber 21, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [1 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [2 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [3 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [4 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [5 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [6 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat 2nd Pass Pages [7 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages [1 of 3], January 5, 2005; February 16, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages [2 of 3], January 5, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages [3 of 3], November 21, 2006; January 11, 2007 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages (photocopies) [1 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages (photocopies) [2 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages (photocopies) [3 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages (photocopies) [4 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages (photocopies) [5 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass pages (photocopies) [6 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat - 2nd Pass Pages (photocopies) [7 of 7], January 5, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat 3rd Pass [1 of 3], February 10, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat 3rd Pass [2 of 3], February 10, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat 3rd Pass [3 of 3], February 10, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages (photocopies) [1 of 5], February 10, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages (photocopies) [2 of 5], February 10, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages (photocopies) [3 of 5], February 10, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages (photocopies) [4 of 5], February 10, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages (photocopies) [5 of 5], February 10, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat - 4th Pass Pages [1 of 3], February 27, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat - 4th Pass Pages [2 of 3], February 27, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat - 4th Pass Pages [3 of 3], February 27, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat 4th Pass, February 27, 2006; March 2, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - What to Eat 4th Pass Pages, February 27, 2006 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat Edited front matter; various chapter excerpts; index, March 22, 2006 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - What to Eat Book Tour [1 of 3], 2006 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - What to Eat Book Tour [2 of 3], 2006 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - What to Eat Book Tour [3 of 3], 2006 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages [1 of 5], February 2, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages [2 of 5], February 2, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages [3 of 5], February 2, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages [4 of 5], February 2, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - What to Eat - 3rd Pass Pages [5 of 5], February 2, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Pet Food Politics
  Series IV contains materials related to the writing of the book Pet Food Politics published in 2008.
  Material has been arranged into two subseries containing Drafts and Contracts as well as Research Files.
  - Subseries A: Drafts and Contracts
    Material is arranged chronologically.
    - Pet Food Politics Draft, April 2008 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Rebecca Nestle's Edits of Pet Food Politics, April 2008 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Pet Food Politics Page Proofs [1 of 2], April 11, 2008; April 15, 2008; May 2008 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Pet Food Politics Page Proofs [2 of 2], April 11, 2008 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Contracts for Pet Food Politics, 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Research Files
    - American Nutrition and Clients, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Aminopterin, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Canadian Per Food, 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Castleberry Dog Food Botulism, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Chem Nutra, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Chinese Food Safety, 2007-2008 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Corn Gluten - South Africa, April 13, 2007; April 19, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Death Counts, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Evanger's Dog & Cat Food Co., April 25, 2008 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - FDA Response, 2007-2008 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Human Food Supply - Pigs, Chicken, Fish, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Lawsuits [1 of 2], 2008-2010 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Lawsuits [2 of 2], 2007-2008 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - MARS Salmonella Schwarzengrund, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Melamine [1 of 2], 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Melamine [2 of 2], 2007 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Menu Foods: Bloggers Response, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Menu Foods: Federal Response, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Menu Foods: Industry Response, 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Menu Foods: PETA Response, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Menu Foods - Stock Prices and Company Information, 2007-2010 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Menu Foods: Veterinarian Response, 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Nutro Zinc, 2009 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Personal Communications [letters, emails, peer reviews], 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - P+G Pet Care, 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Pet Food Recalls, 2006-2007 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Pet Food Recalls, 2005-2009 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Pet Food Recalls, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Petcurean Pet Nutrition, 2004 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Rice Protein, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Tembec, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Timelines, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Wal-Mart, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Wheat Gluten, 2007-2008 (Box 38, Folder 7)
- Series V: Feed Your Pet Right
  Series V contains materials relating the writing of the book Feed Your Pet Right published in 2010. Materials include drafts, editing notes, permissions, and research files.
  Material has been arranged into two subseries comprising Drafts and Permissions as well as Research Files. More information on the arrangement of each subseries can be found below.
  - Subseries A: Drafts and Permissions
    - Nutrition: Cats, 1893-2009 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Ancient Egypt, 1923-2007 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - History of Pet Food [1 of 4], 1935-2009 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - History of Pet Food [2 of 4], 1881-2008 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - History of Pet Food [3 of 4], 1820-2007 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - History of Pet Food [4 of 4], 1858-1965 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Nutrition Problems, 1939-2003 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Nutrition Requirements, 1939-2008 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Horse Meat, 1943-2008 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Brands: Companies, 1987-2008 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Brands: Attitudes/Surveys/Impressions, 2005-2008 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Second Pass [1 of 6], 2008-2009 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Second Pass [2 of 6], 2008-2009 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Second Pass [3 of 6], 2008-2009 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Second Pass [4 of 6], 2008-2009 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Second Pass [5 of 6], 2008-2009 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Second Pass [6 of 6], December 2009 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Feed Your Pet Right: First Pass Pages [1 of 3], November 4, 2009 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Feed Your Pet Right: First Pass Pages [2 of 3], November 3, 2009 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Feed Your Pet Right: First Pass Pages [3 of 3], November 3, 2014 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Permissions Correspondence - Feed Your Pet Right, 2009 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Feed Your Pet Right Advance Uncorrected Proofs, 2010 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Research Files
    Material has been arranged by corresponding chapter of the book. This arrangmenet was provided by Marion Nestle and reflects their original order. Within each chapter folders are listed alphabetically.
    - [Chapter 1] Pet Food Industry [1 of 3], 1974-2010 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 1] Pet Food Industry [2 of 3], 2006-2008 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 1] Pet Food Industry [3 of 3], 1976-2008 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 1] Statistics [1 of 2], 1977-2007 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 1] Statistics [2 of 2], 1992-2008 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 2] AAFCO [Association of American Feed Control Officials], 1936-2007 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 2] Ingredients: Additives, 2006 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 2] Ingredients: Taurine/Carnitine, 1975-2009 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 2] Ingredients: Testing, 1998-2008 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - [Chapter 2] Pets Eating Pets [1 of 2], 1896-2007 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 2] Pets Eating Pets [2 of 2], 1921-2008 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 2] Regulation [1 of 3], 1918-2010 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 2] Regulation [2 of 3], 1921-2008 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 2] Regulation [3 of 3], 1906-2008 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 2] Rendering [1 of 3], 2007-2008 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 2] Rendering [2 of 3], 2004-2007 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 2] Rendering [3 of 3], 1998-2007 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 2] Toxins, 1999-2008 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 3] Advertisements and Material for Slides, 1881-2009 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 3] CBC Analysis, 2007 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 3] Humanification, 2005-2009 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 3] Labels Ingredients Generic [Pet Food], 1948-2008 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 3] Marketing, 1940-2008 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 3] Marketing: Premium, 1995-2008 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 3] Regulation: Labels, 1976-2009 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 4] Aging [1 of 2], 1995-2008 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 4] Aging [2 of 2], 2004-2007 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 4] Allergies, 2001-2008 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 4] Diabetes, 2005-2008 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - [Chapter 4] Dental, 2005 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - [Chapter 4] Gastrointestinal Disease, 2003-2006 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - [Chapter 4] Growth, 2000-2004 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 4] Hairball, 2008 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 4] Heart Disease, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 4] Longevity [1 of 2], 1998-2009 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 4] Longevity [2 of 2], 1968-2007 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 4] Obesity [1 of 2], 2001-2009 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 4] Obesity [2 of 2], 1996-2008 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 4] Renal Disease [1 of 2], 2004-2008 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 4] Renal Disease [2 of 2], 1939-2006 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 5] Antioxidants, 1979-2009 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 5] Chondroitin Sulfate/Glucosamine [1 of 2], 2005-2009 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - [Chapter 5] Chondroitin Sulfate/Glocosamine [2 of 2], 1997-2007 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - [Chapter 5] Omega-3 [1 of 2], 1975-2008 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - [Chapter 5] Omega-3 [2 of 2], 1962-2008 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 5] Probiotics, 1994-2009 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 5] Supplements [1 of 3], 2005-2006 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 5] Supplements [2 of 3], 1967-2008 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 5] Supplements [3 of 3], 1998-2008 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 5] Treats, 1998-2009 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 5] Water, Bottled, 2005-2008 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 6] Alaskan Sled, 2009 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 6] Ancestral, 2007-2008 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 6] Holistic, 2006-2008 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 6] Home-Cooked Foods [1 of 2], 2007 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - [Chapter 6] Home-Cooked Foods [2 of 2], 1998-2008 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - [Chapter 6] Kosher, 2009 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - [Chapter 6] Myths [1 of 2], 1931-2008 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - [Chapter 6] Mthys [2 of 2], 1982-2005 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - [Chapter 6] Natural, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 6] Organics [1 of 2], 2004-2009 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 6] Organics [2 of 2], 2008 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 6] Pet Food Alternatives, 2006-2009 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 6] Raw Food [1 of 2], 2001-2008 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 6] Raw Food [2 of 2], 2007-2008 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 6] Raw Milk, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 6] Vegetarian Diets, 1999-2008 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 7] Animal Pharm The New York Times Magazine, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 7] Animal Rights, 2000-2009 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 7] Animal Research, 2000-2009 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - [Chapter 7] People Eating Pets, 1958-2008 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - [Chapter 7] People Eating Pet Foods, 1935-2009 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 7] Veternarian's Role, 2005-2009 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 7] Veterinary Students, 2003-2009 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 8] Book: Assistants, 2005-2007 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 8] Book Correspondence [1 of 2], 2005-2010 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 8] Book Correspondence [2 of 2], 2006-2009 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 8] Book Outlines/Drafts/Interviews, 2007-2010 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 8] Book/Journals, 2005-2008 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 8] Human Health Effects [1 of 2], 1995-2009 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 8] Human Health Effects [2 of 2], 1984-2007 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 8] Q+A's, 2007 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 8] Resources [business cards], [undated] (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 8] Estate Planning, 2008 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 9] Foreign [pet food], 2008 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 9] Green/Climate, 2009-2010 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 9] Other Animals [Harlan Teklad Global Diets], 2005 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - [Chapter 9] South African [pet food], 2007 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Distributors [A-G], 2008 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Distributors [N-W], 2008 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [A-C], 2006-2008 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [D-E], 2008-2009 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [H-K], 2008-2009 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [M-Na], 2008-2009 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [Nu-Pet], 2005-2008 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [Pre-R], 2001-2008 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Labels [S-Y], 2008 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 10] Pet Food Treat Labels [A-Z], 2007 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - [Chapter 11] Book Illustration Originals, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - [Chapter 11] Global Pet Expo, February 14-16, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 11] Hill's Symposium Evidence-Based Veterinary Clinical Nutrition, November 28-Dcember 1, 2007 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - [Chapter 11] PET FOOD Forum, April 14-17, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - [Chapter 11] Visit to Mars' Waltham Centre for Pet Nutrition, July 30, 2009 (Box 49, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Why Calories Count
  Series VI contains drafts and editing annotations for the book Why Calories Count published in 2012.
  - First Draft [1 of 3], April 2011 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - First Draft [2 of 3], April 2011 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - First Draft [3 of 3], April 2011 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Uncorrected Page Proofs, October 12, 2011 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Comments on First Draft [1 of 3], 2011 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Comments on First Draft [2 of 3], 2011 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Comments on First Draft [3 of 3], 2011 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Edits, December 12, 2011 (Box 50, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Professional Activities
  Series VII contains material relating to Marion Nestle's professional life. This includes articles authored by her, material related to her teaching such as course evaluations, books she was asked to review, correspondence, awards and her day planners.
  Series VII is arranged into seven subseries, divided by her various professional activities. More information on the arrangment within the subseries can be found below.
  - Subseries A: Articles by Marion Nestle
    Subseries A contains drafts and published versions of articles written by Marion Nestle.
    - Nutrition Improvement: An Evaluation of the Nutritional Quality of Meat Served in HRA Food Assistance and Distribution Programs, November 15, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Opinion on Kellogs Advertising, December 3, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Articles: Medical Foods, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Article - Behavioral and Social Influences on Food Choice in Nutrition Reviews vol. 56 Number 5 (Part II), May 1998 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Articles: Dietary Guidelines for the Year 2000: Epidemology in Action Nutrition Vol. 15 No. 6, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Articles in Magazines [1 of 5], 2002-2004 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Articles in Magazines [2 of 5], 2001; 2005 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Articles in Magazines [3 of 5], 1999-2000 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Articles in Magazines [4 of 5], 2002-2004 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Articles in Magazines [5 of 5], 1999 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - How Are We Starving if We're So Fat?, Spring 2006 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Magazine Articles [1 of 3], 2006 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Magazine Articles [2 of 3], 2006 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Magazine Articles [3 of 3], 2006 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Articles: What to Eat, May 9, 2007 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Article: Reading the Food Social Movement World Literature Today Magazine: The Food Issue, January/February 2009 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Articles: Food Culture + Society Paper, 2009 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Notes on San Francisco Chronicle Columns, 2008 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Front-of-Package Food Labels: Public Health or Propaganda? - draft, February 24, 2010 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Writing the Food Studies Movement, March 2, 2010 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: Teaching and Committees
    Subseries B: Teaching and Committees is comprised of materials relating to Marion Nestle's role as a professor, academic administrator, and a consultant or member of food related committees worldwide. Materials include course evaluations, syllabi, department memos, and
    Material is arranged alphabetically. Course Evaluations can be found under "C" and are listed chronologically within that alphabetical schema.
    - [Consultant] - California Department of Food and Agriculture: Milk Nutritional Values, 1999 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - California Vitamin Settlement, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition Food Advisory Committee Appointment, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Center for Science in the Public Interest Annual Reports, 2002; 2006 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Confagricultura Lombardia Consortium, June 2008 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Conference Evaluations: CCMA, July 2012 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Course Evaluations: Field Experience, Spring 1991 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Course Evaluations: Food Policy, Spring 1992 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Course Evaluation: Doctoral Seminar, Fall 1996 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Course Evaluations: Social and Behavioral Determinants of Health, Fall 2004 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Course Evaluations: Food Policy, Spring 2005 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Course Evaluations: Nutrition in Public Health, Fall 2006 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Course Evaluations: Nutrition in Public Health, 2006 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Course Evaluations, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Course Evaluations: Nutrition in Public Health, Fall 2008 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Course Evaluations, Fall 2008 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Course Evaluations, Spring 2008 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Course Evaluations: Food Policy, Fall 2010 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Course Evaluations: Graduate Food Writing Lecture, Spring 2012 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Course Evaluations: Food Sociology, January 2012 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Course Evaluations: Food Policy, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Dublin Institute of Technology, [2000-2003] (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Eating Well Magazine Nutrition and Health Advisory Board, 2006 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - External Advisory Board of the Urban Public Health Program, [1998-2003] (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - The French Culinary Institute, [1994-1997] (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Integrative Nutrition, Summer 2008 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - The Institute of Culinary Education, [2002-2011] (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Journal of Culinary Science & Technology: [Editorial Board Member], December 28, 2004 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - The Lancet - [Consultant], April-May 2005 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Les Dames d'Escoffier International Membership Directory, 2006 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Mauritius U.S. AID Consult, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Mauritius U.S. AID Consult - Final Report, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - NACSEX 1/90 Delegation: Cuba, 1992-1994 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - New School Food Studies Program, 1993-2001 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - The New York Food Museum, 2007; April 29, 1998 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - New York Hall of Science, 2005 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Nutrition: [Databases and Tools for Study of Nutrition], 1984; 1996 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Nutrition for Medical Professionals [1 of 2], [1990-2000] (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Nutrition for Medical Professionals [2 of 2], [1980-1989] (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Nutrition Education for Public Health (US) [1 of 2], [1995-2006] (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Nutrition Education for Public Health (US) [2 of 2], [1980-1995] (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Nutrition in Foreign Education, [1979-1983] (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [1 of 2], [1973-1979] (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [2 of 2], [1972-1992] (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [1 of 2], [1980-1985] (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [2 of 2], [1978-1981] (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Nutrition Summit, April 2009 (Box 55, Folder 2)